http://www.sportdiver.com/privacy-policy

Introduction
At PADI Media, your privacy is important to us. This Privacy Policy applies to all of the products, services, and websites offered by PADI Media. To better protect your privacy, in addition to following PADI’s overall Privacy Policy (LINK), we provide this notice explaining our specific privacy practices and the choices you can make about the way your information is collected and used by PADI Media and its products: Sport Diver Magazine and sportdiver.com; and Scuba Diving Magazine and scubadiving.com.
Note: For questions related to your magazine subscription, please visit the respective magazine’s customer service website.
An overview of the information we may collect
You are able to take advantage of many PADI Media products, services, and websites without providing any information that personally identifies you by name, address, or other personally-identifying information. We only collect personally-identifying information when you voluntarily submit it to us.
Sometimes, we need personally-identifying information in order to provide you with the products and services that you request. Depending upon the product or service, we may ask you for a variety of personally-identifying information. This might include, for example, your name, address, e-mail address, telephone number, gender, and birth date. We may also ask for other information about you, such as your credit card information (when you are making a purchase), interests, income, or education level.
We consider certain identifying information “sensitive.” This includes your credit card number, income level, or any other information that would normally be considered confidential. Some types of personal information will NEVER be requested or collected, such as information on your race or ethnic origin, political opinions, trade union memberships, religious beliefs, health, sex life, or sexual orientation.
You may choose not to provide us with any personally-identifying information. In that case, you can still access and use many portions of our websites; however, you will not be able to access and use those portions of any PADI Media website that require your personal information.
The PADI Media websites, www.sportdiver.com and www.scubadiving.com, include community features, such as online forums and message boards. Information that is posted in these areas becomes public information and the use that any third party makes of this information is beyond our ability to control. You should exercise caution before disclosing any personally-identifying information in these public venues. If you elect to submit content that includes information that can be used to identify you, you must assume that the content can and will be displayed on any website on the Internet.
At PADI Media websites and through certain promotions, you may be able to submit personally-identifying information about other people. For example, you might submit a person’s name and e-mail address to send an electronic greeting card; or, if you order a gift online or offline and want it sent directly to the recipient, you might submit the recipient’s name and address.
PADI Media websites may also provide referral services to help you inform a friend about our websites, products, or services. The types of personally-identifying information that we collect about other people at pages like these may include the person’s name, address, e-mail address, or telephone number. We will only ask you for the information about your friend that we need in order to do what you request.
Our properties may feature Nielsen proprietary measurement software, which will allow you to contribute to market research, such as Nielsen TV Ratings. To learn more about the information that Nielsen software may collect and your choices with regard to it, please see the Nielsen Digital Measurement Privacy Policy at http://www.nielsen.com/digitalprivacy.
We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain information when you visit our websites and directly in emails/communications. These companies may use information you have shared (e.g., click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over, e-mail address) during your visits to this and other websites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. Our partners use this information to recognize you across different channels and platforms over time for advertising, analytics, attribution, and reporting purposes; any information collected is stored in hashed or non-human-readable form. These companies typically use a cookie or third-party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more about this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit http://www.networkadvertising.org or http://www.aboutads.info/choices.
PADI Media websites sometimes may offer contests, sweepstakes, or promotions that are sponsored by or co-sponsored with identified third parties. By virtue of their sponsorship, these third parties may obtain personally-identifying information that visitors voluntarily submit to them in order to participate in the contest, sweepstakes, or promotion. PADI Media has no control over the third-party sponsors’ use of this information. If a third-party sponsor beyond our control will obtain information that you supply us, we will notify you at the time we collect the information from you. For certain promotions, only those who provide us with the requested personally-identifying information will be able to order products, programs, and services, or otherwise participate in the promotion’s activities and offerings.
Some of our websites contain links to other sites. By clicking on these links, you will leave the website operated by PADI Media, and this Privacy Policy will no longer apply. These other sites’ information practices may be different than ours. You should consult the other sites’ privacy notices, as we have no control over information that is submitted to, or collected by, these third parties.
PADI Media Cookie Policy
To make PADI Media websites work properly, and to provide the most relevant products and services to our site visitors and members, we place small data files called cookies on your device. This policy provides you with information about cookies and how to control them for this website. For more information about what a cookie is, please watch the video embedded below.
Cookie List
A cookie is a small piece of data (text file) that a website – when visited by a user – asks your browser to store on your device in order to remember information about you, such as your language preference or login information. Those cookies are set by us and called first-party cookies. We also use third-party cookies – which are cookies from a domain different than the domain of the website you are visiting – for our advertising and marketing efforts. More specifically, we use cookies and other tracking technologies for the following purposes:
Strictly Necessary Cookies
These cookies are necessary for the website to function and cannot be switched off in our systems. They are usually only set in response to actions made by you which amount to a request for services, such as setting your privacy preferences, logging in or filling in forms. You can set your browser to block or alert you about these cookies, but some parts of the site will not then work. These cookies do not store any personally identifiable information.
Cookies used
o
OptanonConsent
o
OneTrustStrictlyNecessary
o
OptanonAlertBoxClosed
Functional Cookies
These cookies enable the website to provide enhanced functionality and personalization. They may be set by us or by third party providers whose services we have added to our pages. If you do not allow these cookies, then some or all of these services may not function properly.
Cookies used
o
OneTrustFunctional
o
has_js
Performance Cookies
These cookies allow us to count visits and traffic sources so we can measure and improve the performance of our site. They help us to know which pages are the most and least popular and see how visitors move around the site. All information these cookies collect is aggregated and is, therefore anonymous. If you do not allow these cookies we will not know when you have visited our site, and will not be able to monitor its performance.
Cookies used
o
_gid
o
OneTrustPeformance
o
_ga
o
_gat_UA-nnnnnnn-nn
Targeting Cookies
These cookies may be set through our site by our advertising partners. They may be used by those companies to build a profile of your interests and show you relevant adverts on other sites. They do not store directly personal information, but are based on uniquely identifying your browser and internet device. If you do not allow these cookies, you will experience less-targeted advertising.
Cookies used
o
GoogleAdServingTest
o
__gads
o
_fbp
o
OneTrustTargeting
Email and Subscriber Data Policy
Information collection and use
We may collect and combine information we have from other sources with information we gather from your interactions with our email messages, including:
•
Email preferences: Preferences we collect from our Preference Center, sign-up widgets on our sites, custom forms or other locations where you provide your email address.
•
Email Interactions: We analyze and store all interactions you take with our email messages. This information includes the kind of content or ads served, viewed or clicked on; the frequency of your activities; purchased a product or service advertised, or took other actions. This allows us to deliver, personalize and develop relevant features, content, advertising and services.
•
Subscriber data: Information collected from online order forms, direct response cards, phone orders, partnerships, agents or other locations where magazine orders are obtained.
•
Credit Card data: Credit card information collected from online order forms or other sources is stored in a secure environment and is used only for the purpose of completing the original transaction, validation, refunds, or if the order is set up to auto-renew then it is used for completing the renewal transaction. Personal credit card information is never shared or used for any analytics or targeting purposes. Orders under auto-renew may be modified to remove the auto-renew feature using the Customer Service link described in the opening paragraph of this data policy.
•
Purchase data: For subscriptions to one of our print or digital magazines, or for products or services you may purchase from our brands.
•
Device IDs, cookies, and other signals, including information obtained from third parties, to associate accounts and/or devices (computers, mobile phones, tablets, etc.) with you: This information includes device specific identifiers and information such as IP address, cookie information, mobile device and advertising identifiers, browser version, operating system type and version, mobile network information, device settings and software data.
•
Location Information: We collect location information about your mailing or shipping address as well as where email messages were opened.
•
Information from others: We collect information about you when we receive it from third parties and affiliates, such as from publicly-available sources.
•
When we obtain information from third-parties or other companies, including but not limited to demographics, purchase activity and interests.
How we use this information
We may collect and combine information we have from other sources with information we gather from your interactions with our email messages, including to:
•
Provide, maintain, improve and develop relevant features and content.
•
Fulfill your requests and when authorized by you.
•
Match and serve targeted advertising (including across devices, platforms and marketing channels) and provide targeted advertising based on your preferences and device activity, subscriber status, affinities, inferred interests and location information.
•
Contact you with information about your subscription, email preferences or interests or with relevant marketing messages.
•
Conduct research.
When and how we share this information with others
PADI Media shares information within its brands and its PADI Organization corporate affiliates. Otherwise, we DO NOT sell, license or share email addresses, unless one of the following applies:
•
With Your Consent. We will share information with companies, organizations or individuals outside of PADI Media when we have your consent.
•
Within PADI Media. Information may also be shared within PADI Media brands and its PADI Organization corporate affiliates.
•
With Partners. We may share your information with non-affiliated companies, as follows:
•
We may share aggregated or anonymous information (including demographic information) with partners, such as advertisers.
•
We allow other companies that show advertisements in our email messages to collect information from your browsers or devices. Other companies' use of cookies and other data collection technologies are subject to their own privacy policies, not this one.
•
We may share aggregated or anonymous information (including demographic information) with partners, such as advertisers. For example, we may tell an advertiser how its ads performed or report how many people clicked on a link after seeing a promotion.
•
We allow other companies that show advertisements in our email messages to collect information from your browsers or devices. Other companies' use of cookies and other data collection technologies are subject to their own privacy policies, not this one.
•
If you provide an email address, we may allow cookie matching with select partners. But, these parties are not authorized to access PADI Media cookies.
Consent you are providing
When you order a magazine, a product, or sign up to receive email messaging from us, you consent to the data processing, sharing, transferring and uses of your information as outlined in our Privacy Policy.
Regardless of the country where you reside, you authorize us to transfer, process, store and use your information in countries other than your own in accordance with this Privacy Policy and to provide you with Services. Some of these countries may not have the same data protection safeguards as the country where you reside.
For information on the data we store and how we use your data, please view our Privacy Policy.
Protecting children's privacy
We do not knowingly collect, use or share information that could reasonably be used to identify children under the age of 18 without prior parental consent or consistent with applicable law.
How we use the information we collect
We use the personally-identifying information that you provide us to fulfill your requests for our products, programs, and services, to respond to your inquiries about offerings, and to offer you other products, programs, or services that we believe may be of interest to you. We sometimes use this information to communicate with you, such as to notify you when you have won one of our contests, when we make changes to subscriber agreements, to fulfill a request by you for an online newsletter, or to contact you about your account with us. We do not use your personal information to make automated decisions.
We may syndicate the publicly available content of our community areas to unaffiliated third-party websites, using RSS or other technologies. The information you have shared in the community areas may be included in this syndication.
We will use the personally-identifying information that you provide about others in order to provide the products or services that you have requested; for example, to enable us to send them your gifts or cards. If you provide us someone else’s personally-identifying information for referral purposes, we may use that information to invite them to visit our websites or to provide them information about our products or services.
If you provide us with your e-mail and/or postal address, we may include that address in e-mail and/or postal address lists that we sell, trade, or rent to third parties. These lists will never contain sensitive information. If you do not wish for your e-mail or postal address to be shared with companies not owned by PADI Media who want to market products or services to you, you have the opportunity to opt out, as described below. You may also opt out of the receipt of any marketing materials from PADI Media as described below.
We may transfer your sensitive personally-identifying information to other PADI offices for internal management and administrative purposes. In addition, your personal data will be transferred to other PADI offices where necessary for the performance or conclusion of our contractual obligations to you or for your benefit. Transfers of personally-identifying information may also be made where necessary for the establishment, exercise, or defense of legal claims.
PADI Media will only share your sensitive personal information with outside companies or individuals in any of the following limited circumstances:
•
When we use trusted businesses or persons to process personal information on our behalf. Before sharing any personal information with outside parties, we require that these parties agree to process such information based on our instructions and in compliance with this Privacy Policy and any other appropriate confidentiality and security measures.
•
When we have a good faith belief that access, use, preservation, or disclosure is necessary to:
1.
comply with applicable law, regulation, or legal process;
2.
enforce the applicable Terms of Service or other agreements and policies on
PADI Media’s websites;
3.
detect, prevent, or otherwise address fraud, security, or technical issues; or
4.
protect against imminent harm to the rights, property, or safety of PADI, PADI Media, its users or the public as required or permitted by law.
•
When you consent. Before we share your sensitive personal information outside of the previously listed circumstances, we will ask you for permission first. Please note that this only applies to sensitive information, as defined above.
We may also use, transfer, sell, and share aggregated, anonymous data about our users for any legal purpose, such as analyzing usage trends and seeking compatible advertisers and partners. In no event will this aggregated data contain any information that could be used to identify individual users of our products or services.
How we protect the safety and integrity of the information we collect
We take appropriate physical, electronic and procedural measures to safeguard and protect your personal information. We use a variety of security measures, including encryption and authentication, to maintain the confidentiality of your personal information. We store your personal information on systems behind firewalls that are only accessible to a limited number of persons, each of whom is required to keep the information confidential. We also take appropriate measures to secure the transmission of sensitive personal information from your computer to the Company’s computers.
When you transmit sensitive, personal information to us, like credit card information, we offer the use of a secure connection to our servers. To the extent you select the secure connection method or your browser supports such functionality, all credit card account information that you supply is transmitted via secure encryption technology. Regardless of these measures, no system connected to the Internet, or data transmission sent over the Internet, can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. We will provide notice if we become aware of any security breach that may affect any sensitive personal information pertaining to you that we have stored on our systems.
PADI Media employees, agents, and contractors who have access to personally-identifying information are required to protect this information in a manner that is consistent with this Privacy Policy and may not use the information for any purpose other than to carry out the services they are performing for PADI Media. These individuals are bound by confidentiality obligations and may be subject to discipline, including termination and criminal prosecution, if they fail to meet these obligations.
PADI Media only collects personal information that is relevant to the purposes for which it will be used. Though we do take appropriate steps to review and update the information that we store to ensure that it is accurate, complete, and current, we also depend on you to update or correct your personal information when necessary.
You may correct or delete any or all of the personal information you have provided to us at any time. Our websites provide means to review and update the personal information that you have provided on each website. To inquire about personally identifiable information that PADI Media has collected about you, or about other ways to correct factual errors in that information, please send us an e-mail at privacy@bonniercorp.com. (Note: Do not use this email address to send questions about a magazine subscription. Instead, please visit the respective magazine’s customer service website.) To protect your privacy and security, we will take reasonable steps to help verify your identity before granting access or making corrections. We will decline to process requests where we cannot verify the identity of the requester. We may also decline to process requests that are automated, repetitive, systematic, or impractical, or that might jeopardize the privacy of others.
In some limited circumstances, such as to resolve disputes, troubleshoot problems, enforce our policies and for necessary legal purposes, we may retain some of information that you have requested us to remove. Therefore, you should not expect that all of your personal information will be completely removed from our databases in response to your requests.
We only use the information we collect for purposes consistent with this policy. If we propose to use your personal information for purposes beyond that explained in this policy, we will provide appropriate notice before doing so and we will provide you with the means to opt out of those uses. We will not use your sensitive personal information for any purposes other than those described in this Policy unless we have obtained your consent.
Your privacy options
If you prefer not to receive e-mail communications from other companies, you may choose to remove yourself from any e-mail lists that we provide to third parties for marketing purposes by sending us an e-mail at emailoptout@bonniercorp.com. In such cases, you will still receive information from PADI Media and its various brands, but we will not share your address information with anyone else.
If you prefer not to receive postal communication from other companies, you may choose to remove yourself from any postal mailing lists that we provide to third parties for marketing purposes by sending us an e-mail at emailoptout@bonniercorp.com, or writing us at PADI Media Group, 221 Lee Road, Suite 109, Winter Park FL 32789. You will still receive information from PADI Media and its various brands, but we will not share your address information with anyone else.
We only want to communicate with you if you want to hear from us. If you prefer not to be contacted at all, you may opt out of receiving any communications from us at any time by notifying us at emailoptout@bonniercorp.com.
You may also notify us by sending mail to the following address:
Online Marketing Department
Attn: Privacy Preferences
PADI Media Group
2211 Lee Road
Suite 109
Winter Park, FL 32789
In all requests, please tell us what communications you would like to opt out of, what means we have been using to contact you (such as your e-mail or postal address), the date of your request, and a way to reach you in case we need to personally contact you in an effort to comply with your request. We reserve the right to send you certain communications, such as technical alerts, without offering you the opportunity to opt out of receiving them.
Questions, Concerns, and Complaints
We take our Privacy Policy seriously, and we regularly review our own compliance with this Policy. If you have any questions or concerns about this Policy, or if you think that we have used your personal information in a manner inconsistent with this Policy, please contact us at:
Privacy Department
PADI Media Group
2211 Lee Road
Suite 109
Winter Park, FL 32789
If we receive a complaint from you, we will contact you in an attempt to address your concerns. If we are not able to resolve a complaint, we will participate in appropriate independent recourse mechanisms as necessary.
